Sujith Gopinath

Sr. Frontend Developer

A self-taught developer with 7+ years of experience in architecting and building frontend applications for B2B and B2C startups (DApp, logistics, food delivery, mobility & service-based companies, etc), I have designed and developed over 8 advanced applications from use-cases and functional requirements. At the moment, I am building decentralized app for wall app and also contributing/learning towards Web3.

$>\!\!<$	sujithgnth@gmail.com
	(+91) 9741978785
in	linkedin.com/in/sujithnath
0	github.com/sujithnath
	sujeith-gopi-nath

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Frontend Engineer - [Full-Time Freelancer]

Stack: Next.js, React + Redux Hooks, Web3, TypeScript, Node, Webpack, Testing, StoryBook

12/2019 - Present

Currently consulting at Wall

- Wall (Singapore Remote): Building a Web3 platform (alpha.wall.app/) with features such as wallets activity feed, User profile, NFT search with wallet address etc. Along with Next.js, I've Implemented custom hooks, redux as state management, styled components, digital wallet integration, framer motion for animations, component modularization.
- SkilloVilla (India): Built an Ed-tech platform with features such as tracks, courses similar to Udemy. Implemented component modularization, redux as state management, custom hooks, dynamic import & code splitting with webpack and firebase for auth purposes.
- WeOne (Norway): Built a CRUD mobility platform and portal for a stealth startup featuring modules such as car uploads, managing organization groups, etc. Implemented better performance using lighthouse in CI/CD pipeline, Immutable.JS with Redux js.
- Applications are built with unit testing using jest + react library, storybook, and scalable architecture which helped the products to scale up with the industrial standard.

Reference: Rahul Dhawani (https://www.linkedin.com/in/rahuldhawani/)

Sr. Frontend Engineer - Loadshare Network

Stack: React + Redux + Hooks, Node, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, TypeScript, AWS, CI/CD pipeline

04/2018 - 09/2019

loadshare.net

Managed the whole frontend logistics application, also closely worked with designers, PM's and cross-team to understand and implement features

- Architected the platform from a legacy codebase (Angular template) to a Node + React + Redux SPA using TS, webpack, and unit test.
- Modularisation of dashboards abstraction layer for APIs, Promises, data store using redux, presentational and container components
- Improved app performance (TTI) with server rendering using node + webpack + prefetch, asset splitting, lazyloading, routing, etc
- Delivered a fully functional logistics app with 13 features (audit s/m, cash on delivery, item tracking, etc)

SKILLS

JavaScript/ES6+ React/Redux
Angular/AngularJS TypeScript
Node.js/Express Next.js
Apollo/GraphQL Webpack
HTML5/CSS3+SCSS

https://sujithnath.github.io/sujithnath/

Docker/Kubernetes

TDD/Unit Testing (Jest, Enzyme, React library)

StoryBook

CI/CD pipeline (GitLab, CircleCI)

D3.js Redis Microservices

Semantics & Accessibility

A/B testing Scrum/Agile

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Chrome extension for NFT's

 Building a chrome extension for loading user NFT's

Shopify Notification Feature

 Using vanilla JavaScript, developing a feature to notify users about the Shopify products

Blog on medium

Angular AOT vs JIT comparison

- Built custom components like dynamic table (in-house plugin) structure allowing customizable configuration
- Took responsibility for tasks/features assigned from understanding the requirement, designing, implementation, and unit testing.

Reference: Gaurav (linkedin.com/in/g-agrawal/)

Frontend Developer - Swiggy

Stack: React + Redux, AngularJS, JavaScript, TDD, Webpack, Mobile hybrid, Node

05/2016 - 04/2018

swiggy.com

Managed the entire vendor application of Swiggy, also helped in scaling the application from 3000 to 25000 daily users

- Built vendor app for restaurant owners from scratch order taking, menu catalogue, discount features, multi-step signup flow, push notification & user metrics
- Built new APIs using Node with express by integrating with microservices services
- Introduced web worker for order polling utilizing push-message, also a self-diagnostic & notification system for vendors to catch browser issues improving CX by 30%
- Developed Vendor PWA utilising PRPL pattern, web APIs like ServiceWorker, IntersectionObserver and Push API
- Integrated few features into the android app serving as a mobile hybrid.
- Performance optimization using webpack such as split & load the chunks using prefetch and preload.
- A member of the Page Performance Team & secured 1st place in the Swiggy hackathon 2017.

Reference: Vinit Bothra (linkedin.com/in/vinitbothra/)

UI Developer - Pipemonk (Acquired by FreshDesk)

Stack: Angular 1, JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, SCSS, Webpack, Firebase, Responsive development

04/2015 - 05/2016

After internal transfer from previous company, I was tasked to maintain website (primarily SEO) and cloud integration application

- Built cloud app with Angular 1, A/B testing + cross-device functionality
- Implemented application with firebase for user data
- Built Pipemonk StoreFront using the EJS template to supply dynamic pages based on user location.

Reference: Vaibav (linkedin.com/in/vaibhav-sinha1989/)

UI Developer - Appiness Interactive

Stack: JavaScript, JQUERY, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, D3, Mobile responsive.

9/2013 - 04/2015

appinessworld.com

Early Stage Service Based Startup.

- Built visualization chart with D3.js, responsive admin app for Schneider Electric
- Built a scalable, lightweight flash video player that became the standard video player in custom ad units

EDUCATION

Bachelors Engineering: Mahatma Gandhi University (08/2008 – 04/2012)

Major in Electronics of Communication